<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Systemic</title><link>https://ezztherose.github.io/blog/tags/</link><description>Latest blog posts from Systemic</description><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://ezztherose.github.io/blog/tags/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Data and Society: quiz</title><link>https://ezztherose.github.io/blog/posts/data_and_society_quiz/</link><pubDate>Fri, 16 Dec 2022 00:16:31 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://ezztherose.github.io/blog/posts/data_and_society_quiz/</guid><description>Data &amp; Society: Quiz This quiz have questions regarding data and the society, there are 13 questions with correct answers.
These questions is designed to open the readers mind and think about the data that are stored, generated and used today.
A full reference list is provided at the end of the quiz for further reading…
Questions Qusestion 1: What is data?
Facts that we can measure quantitatively Knowledge that we can acquire from reliable sources Facts and statistics collected for further analysis Information collected from reliable sources Question 2: According to Kitchin, data is not a “given” but a “taken?</description></item><item><title>MapReduce</title><link>https://ezztherose.github.io/blog/posts/mapreduce/</link><pubDate>Sat, 10 Dec 2022 02:49:02 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://ezztherose.github.io/blog/posts/mapreduce/</guid><description>A summary of MapReduce: Simplified data processing on large clusters Abstract Working with large data sets on a single computer are prone to quickly get complicated, even with a single computation has multiple stets to com- plete before the calculation of the data can begin. This paper provides a solution to run computations on a large data set with the complicated aspect. MapReduce is a set of functions Map and Reduce, this set of functions provide abstraction to automate memory management and par- allelization across large designed clusters, with built in failure handling.</description></item><item><title>First Post</title><link>https://ezztherose.github.io/blog/posts/first-post/</link><pubDate>Tue, 07 Dec 2021 22:20:26 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://ezztherose.github.io/blog/posts/first-post/</guid><description>Testing to create and set up a simple way of sharing my thoughts, with help of Github-pages, and hugo server
Will it update the page?</description></item></channel></rss>